<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio on ilikechicken</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio on ilikechicken</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cu There</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/cu-there/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/cu-there/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Winner of Best Beginner in NHacks VII.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="inspiration"&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team searched for an idea for the student service app for this hackathon. During this process, we were quite perplexed because of the fact that many of the ideas were already put into effect on other apps. While I was thinking about how my sister was graduating high school, I thought about how stressful it was to be a student heading into a post-secondary environment. That is when the idea of CU There was conceived. We wanted to make an organization app for students to compare what their needs were and what school they were comfortable with going to.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>EntryMail</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/email-checker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/email-checker/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="inspiration"&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we&amp;rsquo;re thinking of our problems in school, the notion of clubs arose. Unfortunately, our school clubs were not managed thoroughly and were not secure, and trolls and anonymous users will often disrupt the club on the club Discord server. That&amp;rsquo;s when the idea for EntryEmail was conceived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-it-does"&gt;What it does&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since clubs mostly take place in discord servers, we believed that our project should be related to discord. So we created a discord bot that allows for secure verification in the form of email. EntryEmail is a safe and efficient bot that allows for the denial of bots and trolls. This system restricts access and inspection of certain discord channels. The way to unlock this system would be to verify your email with the school domain and retrieve the code. This code can be entered into the bot, granting you full access to the discord server. This process ensures complete security and guarantees that your discord server cannot be intruded upon. The bot also allows for other features, such as customizing a list of domains you wish to enter, which can filter through bots and trolls. Moderators can also inspect the emails of users that enter to verify them more. EntryEmail is easy to deploy and is a great way to establish an advanced safeguard which protects data privacy and privacy in general for school clubs and communities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>IEMHP</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/imhp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/imhp/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-the-job"&gt;About the Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed a COVID-19 mental health logging platform for children and families, attracting 3,273+ participants
and 140+ practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created 50+ pull requests to front and back-end codebases in a professional team of 10+ members&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilized TypeScript (React), Microsoft Azure, Material-UI, and Linux, showcasing problem-solving skills&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ilikechicken.me</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/ilikechicken-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/ilikechicken-me/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-me"&gt;About Me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a high schooler living in Toronto who is highly interested in CS. I liked to tinker with computers when I was really young and kept the interest until now. I&amp;rsquo;m looking for any CS-related volunteer or intern opportunities, as well as learning more about the field and the future of technology. If you have any questions or want to get in touch, please feel free to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lexis</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/lexis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/lexis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Winner of Best Design in LaunchHacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="inspiration"&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were brainstorming ideas on what we wanted to base our project on for this hackathon, we thought about creating a game that was both fun and educational. We were quite puzzled when confronted with such a simple yet challenging idea. Our team went through countless games that established these two concepts. I thought about how my younger brother had trouble in English class because of the daunting imposition of learning confusing vocabulary. We finally landed on a game that would let you guess how a word was spelled through the pronunciation. We wanted to make a game that was inspired by Wordle but without the limit which allowed for the lobby creator to make as many words as they wished. This would grant teachers or parents a way to teach children how a word sounds and how it is spelled through a point-oriented game. The origin of the name &amp;ldquo;Lexis&amp;rdquo; is the translation of the word &amp;ldquo;Word&amp;rdquo; in Greek.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Recispeed</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/recispeed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/recispeed/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="recispeed"&gt;Recispeed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team is always frustrated when a crucial ingredient is missing while going through recipe books. This is why we developed this reverse search recipe app. In this app, you input everything you have, and it will return a list of recipes you can follow. This app is developed with React and ChakraUI, and dockerized and deployed on hop.io. Hop really made my life a lot easier, because it simplified all the complicated deployment and scales automatically. We will definitely use Hop in our future projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sat Preper</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/sat-preper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/sat-preper/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A timer that records stats for SAT/ACT. It records the time you took for each question, and it visualizes the data after the test for you to improve your score.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Uconnect</title><link>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/uconnect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://ilikechicken.me/portfolio/uconnect/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-the-job"&gt;About the Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Bridging the gap between resource disadvantage and capability to inform future changemakers about the perfect school for them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded by grade 11 student Alfred Shi and other members, UConnect is an organization that informs students about post-secondary education and offers options to fit schools. We at UConnect recognize the privilege that came with private education–and the consequent gap between resource disadvantage and capability for other students across the world. Our aim is to give those students who deserve a better chance at higher education an understanding the right university for them and where their capabilities should land them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>